Going where no car has gone before.
Cars 2 is a animation, family, adventure film directed by John Lasseter.
Star race car Lightning McQueen and his pal Mater head
overseas to compete in the World Grand Prix race.
But the road to the championship becomes rocky as Mater gets caught up in an
intriguing adventure of his own: international espionage.
Mater (voice), played by Larry the Cable Guy.
Lightning McQueen (voice), played by Owen Wilson.
Finn McMissile (voice), played by Michael Caine.
Holley Shiftwell (voice), played by Emily Mortimer.
Sir Miles Axlerod (voice), played by Eddie Izzard.
Francesco Bernoulli (voice), played by John Turturro.
Cars 2 is a 2011 American animated spy action film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
It is the sequel to Cars (2006) and the second film in the Cars franchise.
The film was directed by John Lasseter, and written by Ben
Queen, Lasseter, Brad Lewis, and Dan Fogelman.
Larry the Cable Guy, Owen Wilson, Tony Shalhoub, Guido Quaroni, Bonnie Hunt, and John Ratzenberger reprise their roles from
the first film, with Michael Caine, Emily Mortimer, John Turturro and Eddie Izzard joining the voice cast.
In the film, Mater (Cable Guy) unintentionally gets caught up in a risky espionage mission that threatens both his and Lightning McQueen's
(Wilson) lives during the World Grand Prix, an international racing event showcasing a new alternative fuel called Allinol.
A sequel to Cars was first announced in April 2008 with a tentative summer 2012
release date, which was later moved up to the summer of 2011.
Lasseter was confirmed to be returning as director, while
Lewis was designated as co-director in June 2010.
The film's story was conceived by Lasseter while he was
traveling around the world promoting the first film.
Michael Giacchino composed the film's score, with artists such as Weezer, Robbie
Williams, Brad Paisley and Bénabar contributing tracks for the film.
This was the final Pixar film animated using its old software system,
Marionette, before being officially replaced with Presto in 2012.
With an estimated budget of $200 million, Cars 2 is one
of the most expensive films ever made.
Cars 2 premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on June 18, 2011, and was released in the United States on
June 24, in Disney Digital 3D and IMAX 3D as well as traditional two-dimensional and IMAX formats.
Despite mixed reviews from critics, Cars 2 was a box office success, grossing over $559 million worldwide,
becoming the tenth-highest-grossing film of 2011 and the highest-grossing film of the Cars trilogy.
The film was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the 69th
Golden Globe Awards, but lost to The Adventures of Tintin.
A sequel, Cars 3, was released on June 16, 2017.
The film explores themes of car race, sports, spy, villain, sequel.
The tone is lighthearted.